[Episode 21]
[Bofeng House]
Madam.
I wonder how Ms. Yan is doing.
You usually compete fiercely
for business with Ms. Yan,
but you still care about her quite a bit.
These are two different things.
Haven't you seen
how terrifying those Eternity Pill users are?
The head of the Zhao family and his mother
are both dead.
It's not easy for a woman like Ms. Yan
to build her career out there.
Thanks to Miss Meng, she was saved.
Thank heavens, Miss Meng.
The toxin in her body is gradually reducing.
Just take good care of her health,
and she will be fine.
Thankfully, you're fine.
Thankfully, you came to your senses.
Meng.
Fu Zhi.
Did I hurt you?
It's my fault.
I got you into trouble.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Fu Zhi.
Don't cry.
Thank you for coming late at night,
Your Majesty.
Fu Zhi is now out of danger.
In that case,
why are you still crying?
I'm afraid.
I'm afraid all this is just a dream.
I'm afraid there will be
even more dangerous things ahead.
I'm afraid that even if I give it my all,
I still fail to protect those I care about.
Recently,
seeing you and Miss Yan protect each other,
I have finally come to realize
that without the myriad lights of families
in these streets,
this vast land would mean nothing
but just a cold outline on a map.
But I am afraid
I can't even protect the light
right in front of me.
The light you are sworn to protect
is precisely what I must protect.
You protect it, and I will protect you.
And the common people.
[Censorate]
Come out!
Meng Ting Hui, get out here!
Don't be a coward!
- Get out here!
- Don't be a coward!
Meng Ting Hui!
- Don't move!
- Back off!
Meng Ting Hui!
Calm down!
My father and grandmother
have not yet been laid to rest!
How dare you hide here like a coward!
The birthday feast has turned into a funeral!
They would turn over in their graves!
If I don't give them justice,
how can I let them rest in peace?
How could you let Ling Yun Fei escape?
Today, it is my family that suffers.
What about tomorrow?
Must we all live in misery every day?
- Exactly!
- My son!
You said
you would save money to marry a wife.
I can't believe you died before me.
How am I supposed to go on living?
You ruthless officials!
You don't care about our lives at all!
Hit them!
Hit you all!
Back off!
How could you shamelessly block us?
Yin Qing.
I'm fine, Miss Meng.
Listen, everyone!
I deeply understand your pain and fear.
I'll make a pledge today.
I vow
to eradicate the Eternity Pill
and capture Ling Yun Fei within ten days
to restore peace to the people.
Ten days? Can you really catch him?
Is that for real?
Miss Meng, please think twice!
Ten days is too short!
A pledge is no child's play. It's serious.
I won't change my mind.
And I'm absolutely serious.
Everyone present here can bear witness.
Within ten days,
if I fail, I'll willingly resign
and get punished by law.
Your Majesty,
the leader of Huxiao Gang has escaped.
The whereabouts of the Eternity Pill
are unknown.
If they make a comeback,
the capital will surely come to a crisis.
Today, I impeach Meng Ting Hui
because the people
are boiling with resentment.
If we don't appease them,
I fear great chaos will erupt.
I humbly request Your Majesty
to dismiss and punish her
to appease the people.
Your Majesty.
I've always had differing views from Lord Xu,
but I second his appeal this time.
Ling Yun Fei has wreaked havoc in the capital
because of Meng Ting Hui.
For now,
dismissing her can appease the people
and temporarily stop Ling Yun Fei
from doing evil again.
Absurd!
Huxiao Gang stirred up things,
yet you asked me
to punish the Director of Censorate.
I can't believe
a gang leader, with a poison pill,
has thrown my court into complete chaos.
If an enemy nation invades in the future,
will you all be scrambling to surrender?
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty!
I willingly accept punishment.
The crime of the Eternity Pill case
lies with the Huxiao Gang.
And the responsibility to solve the case lies
with the Censorate, and even more so with me.
I have already made a pledge to the people.
Within ten days,
if I fail to eradicate the Eternity Pill
and capture Ling Yun Fei,
I'm willing to accept any punishment.
Meng Ting Hui,
I see your eagerness
to bring the culprit to justice.
So I'll give you ten days.
Your Majesty, it's her duty to make a pledge.
And today's situation
is the result of her negligence.
According to the Laws of Ning Empire,
she shall be caned 20 times
as a warning to others.
Enough!
Meng Ting Hui has already made a pledge.
As court officials, instead of thinking
about how to suppress the gang together,
you're here attacking your colleague
based on rumors.
I think you're the ones
who deserve to be caned 20 times.
Your Majesty.
As I watched the people suffer,
my heart ached.
I accept the punishment
to apologize to the people.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, we're willing
to be punished with Miss Meng.
I am the Director of Censorate.
My punishment is mine alone to bear.
I'm the Assistant Director,
so I'm also responsible.
I'm also from the Censorate, so I deserve it.
I'm responsible for not solving the case yet.
I'm also responsible for it.
[Shen Mansion]
It must hurt terribly.
You've been weak since childhood.
Even if it's just a flesh wound,
you still need to rest properly.
I didn't act on impulse.
I understand.
Back in the day, I ranked seventeenth
in the first class of scholars.
When I first entered the Hanlin Academy,
I was also full of passion.
Since I married your father,
I've become a housewife, yet without regrets.
But seeing you stick with the Censorate,
I feel as if I'm seeing my former self.
And you're more courageous than me.
I am truly proud of you.
Mother.
I've been down this road,
so I know how difficult it is.
I only did what I should do.
Indeed, the path ahead is hard,
but it shows how good Miss Meng is.
As a woman leading the Censorate,
she publicly made a pledge.
She is a role model for all women.
I must recover from my injuries quickly
and go help her.
Li,
you have truly grown up.
I wonder how Zhi Shu and Nian are doing.
Father, why can Zhi Li eat in her room?
Why do I have to come to the dining hall?
I only walked a few steps,
and my back is already starting to hurt.
If it's too much for you,
just go back and rest.
How can I do that?
Pain aside, I still have to eat.
Besides, you personally cooked this meal.
It would be a shame not to eat it.
Careful, Zhi Shu.
The beating was on the back.
Why does your backside hurt too?
I was caned 20 times.
It takes a long time to recover.
I'm afraid my back is badly mangled.
Nian, take a seat.
Alright.
I think you've spent too much time
in the entertainment places.
Your martial skills are getting rusty.
You need to practice properly.
Look at Nian.
He also took 20 strokes.
Did you hear him complain about the pain?
I'm used to injuries.
In fact,
Zhi Shu travels back and forth
between Changle Street and the Censorate,
which actually takes a lot of mental energy.
You set a good example
as a son of the Shen family.
You lead the Divine Guards
at such a young age.
You used to bravely charge into battle.
And you're considerate at home.
Well done. Come on, let's have a drink.
Thank you, Father.
Father, your good son is tough.
I naturally can't compare to him.
But I'm much stronger than Zhi Li.
She's still bedridden.
Oh, good for you.
As an elder brother,
you're actually mocking your sister?
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
I wonder how Zhi Li is.
She is fine.
Your mother is looking after her.
Eat up.
Master.
The tonic you requested is ready.
Father, let me do it.
I'll deliver it to Zhi Li.
Fine.
Thank you, Father.
Nian's constitution is really excellent.
Father, look.
I'm as insignificant as dust at this home.
All this good food
still can't shut your mouth?
Just eat.
Thank you, Father.
You brat.
Drink.
How did you get beaten like this?
Fu Zhi, don't cry.
I used to have more serious injuries.
It'll be fine in a couple of days.
No matter how badly you were injured before,
you always smiled and said it was nothing.
Those well-read men in the court
not only failed
to help you fight Huxiao Gang,
but also treated you like this.
I'll go confront His Majesty.
You're wholeheartedly devoted to the country.
Why couldn't he protect you?
Miss Yan, are you looking for me?
Your Majesty, Meng only has me as her family.
She's suffered a lot.
She has been framed,
bullied, insulted, and threatened.
Time and again, she nearly lost her life.
Those who targeted her are heinous.
But this time, it was Your Majesty
who personally ordered her punishment.
- Fu Zhi.
- To give an explanation to your officials,
Your Majesty used Meng as a pawn.
But she is the treasure in my heart.
If she fails to solve the case in ten days,
I only beg Your Majesty
to spare her life and dismiss her.
I will take her back to Shazhou.
From then on,
I will never let anyone hurt her again.
I'm done. Please punish me, Your Majesty.
Miss Yan, I promise you.
What you fear will definitely not happen.
I believe
Your Majesty will keep your promise.
And I will keep it in mind.
I'll leave Your Majesty and Meng to talk.
Your Majesty.
Fu Zhi is worried about my safety.
Please do not blame her.
She was right. It was my fault.
I failed to protect you.
I brought the special medicine from Beijian.
It can remove scars and relieve pain.
Let me apply it for you.
I
dare not trouble Your Majesty.
Won't you even let me help
with such a small matter?
This medicine may feel hot
when first applied.
I will be careful.
This mark on your back is quite unique.
A mark?
Which one are you referring to?
I was beaten a lot as a child
and got many scars.
I don't remember.
Your Majesty,
the ten-day deadline is imminent.
Perhaps only by finding the valley now
can we stop the spread of the Eternity Pill.
- I'll go to the outskirts with Yin Qing--
- You don't have to.
I've already ordered Huang Bo
to search for the valley.
Your top priority right now
is to rest and recover your strength.
Otherwise,
I will truly take back your official robes.
Yes, Your Majesty.
The Black Bird is the guardian of Zhongwan.
Royal children tattoo it on their shoulders
with a secret method at a young age,
and it becomes more apparent with age.
Did you see clearly, Your Majesty?
Is the mark on Miss Meng's shoulder
the Black Bird totem?
Although this mark appears alongside scars,
it's very conspicuous.
I vaguely remember
that the Zhongwan royal families killed
by my father back then
also had such a mark on their bodies.
But I was young at the time.
Only you know the most about the past.
Over a decade ago,
Zhongwan coveted our abundant resources.
They provoked us several times.
The late emperor hated their provocation
and personally led the campaign.
Zhongwan resisted relentlessly
but was ultimately subdued
by the late emperor with an iron fist.
Their four-year-old princess also died
within the palace.
Only a squad of warriors broke through
to protect a general's son.
Based on age,
Miss Meng and their princess are
of the same age.
But didn't their princess already die?
Now it seems
the dead princess might not be the real one.
Perhaps the remnants of Zhongwan
protected their royal bloodline
for the restoration of their country.
Huiyin House
and the Blood Moon Society behind it
have been plotting the restoration all along.
Situ Xue is very close to Miss Meng.
Perhaps Miss Meng is one of them,
deliberately infiltrating the court.
The ancestors have clearly stipulated
that the surviving people of Zhongwan
shall be slaves
and shall not be officials.
The late emperor's intention was to guard
against those who viciously disrupt the court
and harm the common people.
So far, the remnants of Zhongwan
have been plotting to restore their country.
Their royal bloodline
must be completely eradicated.
Are you asking me to kill Miss Meng?
I have already retired
and should not be discussing state affairs.
However,
Your Majesty is so close to Meng Ting Hui.
There are already criticisms outside.
It's truly worrisome.
Your Majesty, I hope you'll be cautious
and be wary of Meng Ting Hui
and also the Blood Moon Society.
Only in this way
can you be prepared for the unexpected
and stabilize the nation.
Father, don't worry.
His Majesty has long ordered me
to keep an eye on Huiyin House
and secretly watch the movements
of the Blood Moon Society.
His Majesty will absolutely
put national interests above all.
It's just that Miss Meng's identity
indeed needs to be re-examined.
This matter concerns the feud
between the two nations.
I will absolutely not take it lightly
or act on emotion.
Regarding Meng Ting Hui and the Censorate,
I will naturally remain wary.
Wise decision, Your Majesty.
Before the matter is concluded,
we will certainly keep our mouths shut.
Zhi Shu, remember this.
Father, I'll naturally keep it a secret.
[Censorate]
We've searched their storehouses,
secret cellars,
and even the caves in the mountain,
but failed to find a single Eternity Pill.
Moreover, the area for dozens of li
around Huxiao Gang is rocky.
It cannot be the place
where the poison pill is made.
Logically speaking,
Ling Yun Fei is severely injured.
If he doesn't want to bleed to death,
he won't hide
in a place far from the capital.
Nian, you led men to search the valleys
on the outskirts of the capital.
Did you truly not find any clues at all?
There are 17 valleys
on the outskirts of the capital.
Each one was compared against the painting.
Huang Bo has led the Divine Guards
deep into the miasma forest,
but no news yet.
Huxiao Gang's lair has now been destroyed,
but as long as Ling Yun Fei is still alive,
given his extreme personality,
he will surely plot a more vicious revenge.
Miss Meng, your injury?
It's fine.
Zhi Li, write a memorial to the throne now
to request His Majesty
to send reinforcements.
We must find the place
where the poison is made as soon as possible.
Otherwise, disaster would loom.
Tighten the iron chains!
Yes.
Master, according to your instructions,
the dosage of the Fuqing herb
has been tripled.
What fascinating fragrance!
But it's not enough yet.
Increase the dosage.
Collect all the Fuqing herbs
in Wangxian Valley within ten days.
This time, either Meng Ting Hui
or I will die.
Then you can prepare to die.
Mr. Shangguan, you actually came.
It seems you can't sit back anymore.
You spread the Eternity Pill at Bofeng House
to get revenge on Meng Ting Hui.
Now the whole city is under martial law.
You are destroying our business.
You always hide
and earn small profits.
Is this the vision of a coward like you?
Listen up.
If you trouble Meng Ting Hui again,
I will have to kill you.
What exactly is your relationship with her?
You talk about her
and protect her at every turn.
Our business ends here.
Do you think
I will just sit still and wait for death?
Look,
this is the true power of the Eternity Pill.
I will use an army of poison men
to massacre the capital.
Meng Ting Hui is doomed.
[Temporary Closure Notice]
I originally wanted to earn money
to buy a big house
and enjoy a good life with you.
In the end, I lost everything.
This time, thanks to you,
I escaped from the jaws of death.
It's thanks to Mr. Shen.
To get the antidote for you,
he even pawned the jade pendant bestowed
by the late emperor.
But considering his eagerness to save you,
His Majesty did not blame him.
But I heard from Zhi Li
that Grand Tutor Shen punished him
by making him kneel for three days.
He is sincere towards you.
Having escaped death this time,
I now realize
that a friend in need is a friend indeed.
Since you have given your all to save me,
I must live even better.
Bofeng House will be closed for two months.
And I will create more new dishes.
When it reopens,
I will definitely amaze all the diners here.
But you haven't fully recovered yet,
and Bofeng House is not safe.
Stay at the Censorate for now,
and I can look after you.
You've been busy looking for Ling Yun Fei.
Do you have time for me?
The deadline is approaching.
But all leads on Ling Yun Fei have gone dead.
The Light Cavalry has been searching valleys
for days, but no news yet.
Even His Majesty has not come
to the Censorate for many days.
It is quite strange.
Alright, let's not think about it anymore.
Let's go out for a walk.
- Yin Qing.
- Miss Meng, Ms. Yan.
You went to Huiyin House?
Miss Situ often goes to the border
and has some rare medicinal herbs
as well as candles and incense.
I need them to take care of Ms. Yan's health.
Thank you.
Captain Di has gone to check the valleys.
Has he found any clues?
Why hasn't the Light Cavalry
sent a word to the Censorate so far?
His Majesty personally
deployed the Divine Guards.
All information is reported
directly to His Majesty.
But I have good news.
I happened to hear
that the Light Cavalry found a valley
that somewhat resembles the one
in the painting.
But your memorial to His Majesty
requesting more men
has not been approved yet.
The Divine Guards should
be assisting the Censorate in handling cases.
Now they don't report to me.
I need to borrow your candle.
[Imperial Study]
Your Majesty, according to the Light Cavalry,
Huang Bo went missing
at the last unsearched valley.
It is called Wangxian Valley.
The terrain there is dangerously steep.
It is shrouded in mist all year round,
hindering visibility.
The Light Cavalry found Huang Bo's dagger
at the entrance of the valley.
Huang Bo never loses his personal belongings.
Could he have encountered danger?
You will immediately lead the Light Cavalry
to search the mountain.
Does this matter need
to be reported to Miss Meng?
We haven't found any Fuqing herb yet
in that valley.
There is no need to tell her for now.
- First, investigate thoroughly.
- I see.
Your Majesty, I'm guilty!
Not again.
As Huang Bo is away,
he has been nagging nonstop.
Help me stop him before you go.
Yes.
His Majesty personally went
to the Huxiao Gang.
I'm worried about His Majesty's safety.
I couldn't get any peace of mind.
I've failed the late emperor!
Captain Di, lend me your sword.
I'm going down
to join the late emperor right now.
Captain Di, I am just so worried sick.
His Majesty stays up late
reviewing memorials.
It seems he caught a chill.
I have prepared medicine.
Your Majesty.
[Nine Nine Nine]
Take good care of your health!
- Your--
- You may leave.
Your Majesty, take good care of your health!
Your Majesty!
Can you stop bothering me?
So Your Majesty finds me bothersome.
That's why you haven't come
to the Censorate recently.
I thought Chief Steward You came.
This is something from Huiyin House.
Miss Situ specially made them.
They can calm the mind.
Your Majesty has been mentally bothered
with the Eternity Pill matter.
You can give it a try.
You didn't especially come
just for this gift, right?
The memorial I submitted
requesting additional personnel
hasn't been approved yet.
Do you know this image?
No, I don't.
This is the Black Bird revered by Zhongwan.
It is said to be able to tell fortunes
and protect the nation.
Later, Zhongwan submitted to the Ning Empire.
Do you think I need to change the policies
towards their surviving people?
Your Majesty.
I have only read about Zhongwan in books.
I don't know the actual situation.
Miss Yan has just barely escaped danger.
I also don't want you to face danger again.
I have decided to make other plans.
The Censorate will stay out of this case.
Your Majesty, I can keep it professional.
I was worried sick about Fu Zhi.
Personally, I want to avenge her,
but so what?
The Censorate has been pursuing Ling Yun Fei.
And I am the right person for this case.
I hope Your Majesty will change your mind.
Ling Yun Fei is relentlessly targeting you.
I worry about your safety.
Just have a couple of days off.
I made this decision out of concern for you.
I feel you've been acting strangely.
Are you hiding something from me?
You don't need to overthink it.
Just do what I said.
Your Majesty, among all the court officials,
who knows Ling Yun Fei better
than the Censorate?
If you're worried about me,
you can send someone to follow me.
But if you pull the Censorate
out of this case,
I will go myself.
Your Majesty, since you don't trust me,
I don't need to wait for your approval.
I already know where Wangxian Valley is.
Since the day we met,
I have known what kind of person you are.
Trusting you means
allowing you to go into danger.
I want my country to be stable,
but I also want you to return safe and sound.
The terrain of Wangxian Valley is complex.
I'll go there with you.
You're awake.
Wonderful.
I was worried you would keep sleeping.
Don't move.
I'm just listening to your heartbeat,
checking how your recovery is going.
After drinking my medicine,
the snake venom inside has been removed.
But it will take a few more days
to heal your leg injury.
For now, you can't be up and about.
Thank you for saving my life.
You're welcome. My name is Luo.
I'm a resident of Wangxian Valley.
What's your name?
My name is Huang Bo.
Huang Bo.
Luo, let me help you.
Your leg injury hasn't healed yet.
Don't move around.
Huang!
Master!
Be careful.
Why are you all here?
Luo,
the lot of us came uninvited.
Sorry to trouble you.
No trouble at all.
Usually, strangers rarely come here.
I'm happy to host many guests.
Besides, all of you are pretty
and dressed much better than we are.
Luo,
did you see the same scenery in the valley?
The scenery here is beautiful,
surrounded by clouds and mist.
Looking up from the bottom of the valley,
it's like a fairyland.
The scenery in this painting
does look similar.
Luo, do you know a flower--
Luo,
I see many flowers in this courtyard.
May I ask what they are used for?
Tomorrow is the Flower Festival here.
I'm busy preparing flower cakes
for the festival.
I'll leave you all to rest and talk.
If you need anything, just let me know.
Miss Meng,
I was about to ask about the Fuqing herb.
Why did you...